Santiago Ramon Alvarez

(+57) 3057668478 stiago4r@gmail.com https://github.com/stiag0 https://www.linkedin.com/in/santiago-alvar ez-b6a530233/

Developer with a background in web, mobile and game development, having 2+ years of practice and leadership building interactive experiences. Disciplined, organized, humble and accessible person. Committed to good morals, continuous learning, innovation and development of optimal solutions.

Great enthusiastic teamwork, considered cautious, assertive, helpful and creative.

EXPERIENCE

Tigo Colombia software Developer – 2021- 2022

Develop multiple automations on microsoft environment to resolve delays operational timelapse using excel **macros**, power-Query (**DAX**) and **Power Automate** to deploy software with a dynamic response compared to classic excel usages. deliver quality products and made several on-boarding processes to new developers.

- Mentored team members in development, issues and technical Progression.
- Designed a normalyzer to format data-sets as a tool to improve the consumers data ratio and make it more accessible to the operational team.

vba, DAX, PowerAutomate

Centraldelbarbero.com Software Developer & CEO – 2019-Present Developed, launched and managed the commercialization of a

successful app along with other engineer using scrum, Firebase and Angular

- Collaborated with other developers to identify and alleviate software errors and inefficiencies.
- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.
- Got over 5,000 downloads, more than 300 users online at the same time and more than 3,000 usd in revenues.

javascript , TypeScript, Angular, Angular, CSS

Central de belleza © showcase salesman – 2010-2013

Was my first job and become a complete new challenge to me but after the training time i become a successful deal closer, of course i was better selling hair dryer, hair straighteners or ellectrodomestics in general, but not let that limit myself and learn a lot of other products and even learn how to combine colors to recommend a nail polish or hair dye.

Perform a social network integration business.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: python, Sql, MongoDB. Comfortable: java, C++, JavaScript, C#. **Frameworks and Tools:** Angular, Spring, Spring boot, Mysql, Sql Server, Postman, jmeter, Unity **Languages:** English, Fluent; Spanish, Native;

EDUCATION

Eafit University – Medellín, Colombia. Bachelor of Science, Systems Engineering, 2022